Archana.G.S Data Scientist

Portfolio Linkedin Upwork Github Published paper

Milpitas,CA 669 231 9980 archanags001@gmail.com

Data Scientist with over 4 years of experience, specializing in machine learning and artificial intelligence. Demonstrated success in creating machine learning models, conducting in-depth data analysis, and applying problem-solving skills. Eager to contribute my expertise to the dynamic and challenging field of AI.

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist — **Wonder Chrome** (December 2021 - PRESENT)

- Conducted A/B testing experiments to assess the effectiveness of various promotion strategies, resulting in a remarkable 24% increase in revenue.
- Developed machine learning models using scikit-learn to optimize pricing strategies, leading to a substantial 12% boost in profit.
- Led full data lifecycle: collection, cleaning, feature engineering, modeling, validation, and dashboard/report creation.
- Proficiently developed complex SQL queries, procedures, and reports using Redshift, Sagemaker, SQL, and Python to meet diverse client needs.
- Developed a Large-scale multi-label text classification model using Tensorflow and Keras to enhance text analysis capabilities.

Data Scientist — Freelance (January 2019 - PRESENT) Upwork

- Top Rated freelancer, representing the top 10% of Upwork talent.
- Collaborated with 5 clients to understand their company needs and devise data-driven solutions.
- Facilitated end-to-end development, testing, and monitoring of analytical models for 5 clients.
- Designed and developed a News search tool leveraging LLM and Langchain technologies, enhancing the efficiency of information retrieval and analysis.
- Efficiently managed Azure Databricks, executed ETL, and developed ML models for small and large datasets(125GB, 1B rows), automated scheduling, tracked experiments, implemented Auto ML, and maintained resource efficiency

Artificial Intelligence Engineer intern — Uniquify Inc(August 2021-October 2021)

- Led training and development of neural networks using TensorFlow, optimizing models for enhanced accuracy and efficiency.
- Conducted comprehensive experiments with TensorFlow scripts and analyzed results to enhance model performance and understand framework dynamics.
- Played a key role in debugging and improving an automation framework for neural network and TensorFlow scripts, streamlining workflows and ensuring reliable model training.
- Developed advanced image processing and segmentation algorithms to solve complex problems, contributing to project success.

Data Analyst — Centriqe Inc (February 2020 - January 2021)

- Developed an NLP system using NLTK to automate text analysis, resulting in a significant 39% reduction in manual analysis efforts, improving efficiency and accuracy.
- Leveraged analytical and technical expertise to provide actionable insights and proposals, driving business improvement strategies.
- Designed and implemented a range of predictive models, including classification and forecasting models, using various machine learning tools to solve complex business challenges.
- Identified trends, key metrics, and critical data points, generating insightful
 dashboards using a variety of data visualization tools to facilitate data-driven
 decision-making.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Python, R, Core Java, Basic JavaScript

Machine Learning and DeepLearning: TensorFlow, Keras, CNN, RNN,PyTorch

Natural Language Processing

(NLP): NLP techniques, Hugging Face, Langchain, Transfer learning,SpaCy, BeautifulSoup

Computer Vision: OpenCV, Transfer learning,YOLO, VGG16, ResNet

Generative AI: LLM, Langchain, Hugging Face, OpenAI, Gemini, LLAMA

Cloud Services: AWS, Azure

Database & Data Storage: SQL, MongoDB

Data Visualization Tools:

Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn

Big Data: PySpark

Dashboard Development:

Power BI, Tableau, Retool, Dash, Streamlit, Kibana

EDUCATION

Master of Technology in Electronics with specialization in Signal processing

GPA: 4.0

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and communication Engineering **GPA: 3.5**

WORK ELIGIBILITY:

EAD(Employment Authorization Document)